- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat instrumental music]
[欢快的器乐]
*
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
- Oh, why can't I
get to sleep?
- 哦，为什么我不能
睡觉了吗？
Let's try it again.
[sighs]
让我们再试一次。
[叹气]
Warm milk.
温牛奶。
White noise machine.
白噪声机。
[machine bubbling]
【机器冒泡】
[groans]
[呻吟]
Dim lights.
灯光昏暗。
[groans]
[呻吟]
* Sleep, little Squidward,
catch some winks *
* 睡觉吧，小章鱼哥，
眨眼*
* Everything and everybody
clearly stinks *
* 一切和每个人
明显有臭味*
- [belches]
- [screams]
- [打嗝]
- [尖叫]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Oh, yeah!
Fizz Bomb Cola!
哦，是啊！
嘶嘶炸弹可乐！
- Fire in the hole!
- 洞里着火了！
- [belches]
- [打嗝]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- [yelling]
Hey!
- [大喊]
嘿！
Will you two psychopaths
keep it down?
你们两个精神病患者会吗
保持低调？
- Oh, hi, Squidward.
How ya doing?
-哦，嗨，章鱼哥。
你怎么样？
- Horrible!
I haven't slept for three days.
- 太可怕了！
我已经三天没睡觉了。
- Hey, that's great!
- 嘿，太好了！
- It is not great.
- 这不太好。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
I've got an audition
我有一个试镜
with the Bikini Bottom
Philharmonic Orchestra
与比基尼泳裤
爱乐乐团
tomorrow morning,
and I'm a nervous wreck.
明天早上，
我神经衰弱。
- Why don't you
try taking a walk?
- 你为什么不呢
尝试散步吗？
Works for me.
- You know, normally,
对我有用。
- 你知道，通常情况下，
I jump up and scream
when you appear like that.
我跳起来尖叫
当你出现那样的时候。
But I'm so tired,
I'm just gonna take
但我实在是太累了
我只是要采取
your stupid advice.
你愚蠢的建议。
- No, Patrick, no!
- 不，帕特里克，不！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- We've got to keep it quiet.
- 我们必须保持安静。
[stomach gurgling]
[肚子咕咕叫]
- Tell my parents
I love them.
- 告诉我的父母
我爱他们。
- Ahh!
[grunts]
- 啊！
[咕哝]
[inhales, grunts]
[吸气，咕哝]
Hit the dirt!
撞上泥土！
- [belches]
- [打嗝]
[gulps]
[吞咽]
[sighs]
[叹气]
That was sheer beauty.
那是纯粹的美丽。
- Taking a walk...walk...
- 散步...散步...
walk.
走。
[groans]
[呻吟]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
[sheep bleating]
[羊咩咩叫]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Home.
家。
[door creaks]
[门吱吱作响]
[both munching]
[两人都在咀嚼]
[creepy music]
[令人毛骨悚然的音乐]
- SpongeBob?
What's happening?
- 海绵宝宝？
发生什么事了？
- I don't know.
- 我不知道。
*
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- Ahh!
[grunts]
- 啊！
[咕哝]
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
- Aw, poor guy
was just sleepy.
- 噢，可怜的家伙
只是困了。
Looks like we're
gonna be here a while.
看来我们是
会在这里待一段时间。
See you in the morning, Patrick.
早上见，帕特里克。
- Oh, yeah.
I should probably...
- 哦，是的。
我或许应该...
[sighs]
[叹气]
[snores]
[打鼾]
- [meows]
- [喵]
- Aww.
- 哇。
Aww.
哇。
[all snoring]
[全都打呼噜]
- [crows]
- [乌鸦]
- [meows]
- [喵]
- [yawns]
- [哈欠]
[yells]
[喊叫]
This isn't my rug!
Where--where am I?
这不是我的地毯！
我在哪里？
Who am I?
我是谁？
[panting]
Who am I?
[气喘吁吁]
我是谁？
How am I?
- Patrick, Patrick, calm down.
我怎么样？
- 帕特里克，帕特里克，冷静点。
You're at my house.
Oh, and that is your rug.
你在我家。
哦，那是你的地毯。
- Oh, yeah.
- 哦，是的。
Ruggie, Ruggie, Ruggie.
鲁吉，鲁吉，鲁吉。
Ruggie, Ruggie,
Ruggie.
鲁吉，鲁吉，
鲁吉.
- Squidward, time to wake up.
- 章鱼哥，该起床了。
Wake up, little Squidward.
醒醒吧，小章鱼哥。
Patrick,
Squidward won't wake up.
帕特里克，
章鱼哥不会醒来。
- Ruggie, Ruggie,
Ruggie, Ruggie!
- 鲁吉，鲁吉，
鲁吉，鲁吉！
[yelling]
Wake up, little Squidward,
[大喊]
醒来吧，小章鱼哥
wake up!
醒醒吧！
- Maybe we should
get him up.
-也许我们应该
把他扶起来。
[chanting together]
Wake up, wake up,
[一起念诵]
醒来吧，醒来吧，
wake up, wake up!
醒醒，醒醒！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[coffee dripping]
[咖啡滴落]
[hissing]
[嘶嘶声]
both: Wake up!
两人：醒醒！
- [snores]
- [打鼾]
[electric guitar trilling]
[电吉他颤音]
both: Wake up!
两人：醒醒！
- [snoring]
- Patrick, this is bad.
- [打鼾]
- 帕特里克，这很糟糕。
Squidward won't make
his audition
章鱼哥不会做
他的试镜
with the Philharmonic Orchestra.
What can we do?
与爱乐乐团合作。
我们能做什么？
- Oh, we'll have to create
another Squidward in a lab.
- 哦，我们必须创造
实验室里的另一个章鱼哥。
- Patrick, you are a genius!
- 帕特里克，你是个天才！
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[machinery grinding]
【机械磨削】
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[both gasp]
[两人都喘气]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[growling]
[咆哮]
*
[smashing]
[粉碎]
- Eureka!
- 尤里卡！
- No, Patrick.
It didn't work.
- 不，帕特里克。
它不起作用。
- Ooh, we've tried everything
under the ocean,
- 哦，我们已经尝试了一切
在海洋之下，
and we failed.
我们失败了。
If only we could just
crawl up inside Squidward
如果我们能
爬进章鱼哥里面
and play him like a puppet.
并把他当作一个木偶。
- That's it!
We could crawl up
- 就是这样！
我们可以爬上去
inside Squidward
and play him like a puppet!
章鱼哥里面
把他当木偶玩！
- Oh, whose dumb idea was that?
- 哦，这是谁的愚蠢主意？
- Yours.
- 你的。
- Well, it sounds good to me.
- 嗯，对我来说听起来不错。
- Okay, Patrick, you go in first
- 好吧，帕特里克，你先进去
and control his arms and legs.
并控制他的手臂和腿。
Then I'll go in
and control the brain.
然后我就进去
并控制大脑。
- Okay.
- 好的。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Eww.
呃。
[laughs]
[笑]
It tickles.
很痒。
- How's that feel, buddy?
- 感觉怎么样，伙计？
- Not bad.
Okay, get on my shoulders.
- 不错。
好吧，站到我的肩膀上吧。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Okay, Patrick, I'm gonna see
if I can make Squidward talk.
好吧，帕特里克，我会看看
如果我能让章鱼哥开口说话。
[as Squidward]
My name is Squidward,
[饰演章鱼哥]
我的名字是章鱼哥
and I think SpongeBob
is a lamebrain.
我认为海绵宝宝
是一个跛脑。
[laughs]
[笑]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Wow, you sound more like him
than--
哇，你听起来更像他
比——
than Squidward.
[laughs]
比章鱼哥。
[笑]
- All right, Patrick,
we've got a date
- 好吧，帕特里克，
我们有个约会
at the Bikini Bottom
Philharmonic.
在比基尼底部
爱乐乐团。
Let's get going.
我们开始吧。
[as Squidward]
Whoa, whoops.
[饰演章鱼哥]
哇哦。
Watch out.
Take it easy.
当心。
别紧张。
[jackhammer pounding]
[手提钻敲击声]
- Hey!
- 嘿！
- Left foot, right foot.
- 左脚，右脚。
[both exclaiming]
[两人惊呼]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- [frantic muttering]
- [疯狂的嘀咕]
Whoa!
Excuse me.
哇！
打扰一下。
Sorry.
- Yeah?
对不起。
- 是的？
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[explosion]
[爆炸]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Pardon me.
- 请原谅我。
- Hey, Twinkle Toes,
- 嘿，闪闪发光的脚趾，
you're in a no dancing zone.
你处于禁止跳舞的区域。
Now beat it.
现在打败它。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Patrick, I just realized
I don't know
帕特里克，我刚刚意识到
我不知道
where the concert hall is.
音乐厅在哪里。
[epic music]
[史诗音乐]
Uh, let's ask someone.
呃，我们去问问某人吧。
- Whoa!
- 哇！
[as Squidward]
- Excuse me, ma'am.
[饰演章鱼哥]
- 对不起，女士。
I'm looking for
the concert hall.
我正在寻找
音乐厅。
[grunting]
Whoa!
[咕噜声]
哇！
- Young man, you don't need
a concert hall.
- 年轻人，你不需要
音乐厅。
You need a hospital.
你需要一家医院。
- Great Neptune,
you're hideous!
- 伟大的海王星，
你太丑了！
I manage a freak show,
and you're exactly
我主持了一场怪诞表演，
而你正是
the kind of act I need.
我需要的那种行为。
- Mommy, look.
- 妈妈，看。
It's Frankenstein!
这是弗兰肯斯坦！
[all murmuring]
[大家窃窃私语]
- Oh, Patrick!
That bus is going
- 哦，帕特里克！
那辆公共汽车正在行驶
to the concert hall!
去音乐厅！
[all murmuring]
[大家窃窃私语]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[coin clinking]
[硬币叮当作响]
Patrick, do you
have any change?
帕特里克，你吗
有什么变化吗？
- One second.
- 一秒钟。
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
- Hey, I wasn't born yesterday.
That'll be three fares.
- 嘿，我不是昨天出生的。
那就三块钱吧
[coins clinking]
[硬币叮当作响]
Hmm, what some people
won't do to cheat the system.
嗯，有些人
不会欺骗系统。
[fanfare]
[大张旗鼓]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- And don't come back!
- 别回来！
- Oh, man.
That conductor's brutal.
- 哦，伙计。
那个指挥太残忍了
[both grunting and exclaiming]
[一边咕哝一边惊呼]
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- Oh, oof!
- 哦，哦！
- [as Squidward]
I was just, oh, um,
- [作为章鱼哥]
我只是，哦，嗯，
the thing is not on the thing.
Oh, uh...
东西不在东西上。
哦，呃...
- Who is that imbecile?
- Squidward Tentacles.
- 谁是那个低能儿？
- 章鱼哥的触手。
Apparently he's
a clarinet player.
显然他是
单簧管演奏者。
- All right,
whenever you're ready.
- 好吧，
每当你准备好时。
- [whispering]
The clarinet,
- [低语]
单簧管，
where's his clarinet?
- Oh, I got it.
他的单簧管在哪里？
- 哦，我明白了。
- Ew, why'd you put it there?
- 呃，你为什么把它放在那里？
- I guess I never actually
- 我想我从来没有真正
thought of the moment
where we'd have to play it.
想到那一刻
我们必须在哪里玩它。
- Let's see, the ability
to play clarinet
- 让我们看看，能力
演奏单簧管
has got to be
in his brain somewhere.
必须是
在他大脑的某个地方。
It's just a matter
of squeezing it out.
这只是一个问题
把它挤出来。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[clarinet squeaking]
[单簧管吱吱声]
[grunting, clarinet squeaking]
[咕噜声，单簧管吱吱声]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
All right, thank you, next!
好的，谢谢，下一个！
[delicate melody]
[细腻的旋律]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
both: Huh?
两人：啊？
*
- He's magnificent.
- 他太棒了。
- What--what's going on here?
Where am I?
- 这--这是怎么回事？
我在哪里？
I'm at the audition.
我正在参加试镜。
I'm playing,
but I'm not in control.
我正在玩，
但我无法控制。
I--I feel like I've been
taken over by something.
我——我感觉我已经
被某物接管。
- What's going on?
- 这是怎么回事？
- I don't know what's happening.
- 我不知道发生了什么事。
I'm losing control!
我要失去控制了！
- Must...gain...
- 必须...获得...
control!
控制！
- That's an unusual
playing style, but still.
- 这是一个不寻常的
打球风格不过如此。
He sounds magnificent.
他听起来很伟大。
- Patrick, I don't think I can
- 帕特里克，我想我不能
command his brain much longer.
指挥他的​​大脑更长时间。
- Me neither, SpongeBob.
- 我也一样，海绵宝宝。
- What was that--
SpongeBob? Patrick?
-那是什么--
海绵宝宝？帕特里克？
You're inside me?
Oh, how did this happen?
你在我体内吗？
哦，这是怎么发生的？
Get out of my mind!
从我的脑海里滚出去！
Get out of my body.
Just--just--just get out!
从我的身体里滚出去。
就——就——就出去！
[muttering]
[嘀咕]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- [gagging]
- [作呕]
[spits]
[吐口水]
both: Ta-da.
两人：哒哒。
- Oh, I am going to
lambaste you two.
- 哦，我要去
骂你们两个。
- You're a wizard.
A magical, musical wizard.
- 你是个巫师。
一位神奇的音乐奇才。
- I--huh? Oh.
- 我 - 嗯？哦。
- Yes, yes!
- 是的，是的！
Oh, bring us to ecstasy,
maestro.
哦，让我们欣喜若狂，
大师。
- I envy you common people.
- 我羡慕你们这些普通人。
For you are about to have
the glorious honor
因为你即将拥有
光荣的荣誉
of hearing me play
Gustav Mollusk's
听我演奏
古斯塔夫软体动物
Symphony Number Five
in C sharp minor.
第五交响曲
升C小调。
For I am in
complete control.
因为我在
完全控制。
[shrill squealing]
[尖锐的尖叫声]
[both groaning]
[两人都呻吟]
[glass shattering]
[玻璃破碎]
[cawing and honking]
[呱呱叫和鸣喇叭]
[ice crashing]
[冰崩塌]
[buildings rumbling]
[建筑物隆隆作响]
[both snoring]
[两人都打呼噜]
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
[delicate melody]
[细腻的旋律]
Hmm? Huh?
唔？啊？
*
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]